We're not following you anymore.
Have you considered why you're having trouble responding to Smallfry's request?
Do you even want to put in the effort at all?
And if you can't understand that fact, you're every bit the despot king you used to be.
So, is there something the matter with Kageyama today?
Huh? There's nothing that I know of.
Well, nothing physically, anyway.
Hmm.
You know, I remember when Kageyama was in middle school,
everyone kept talking about this up-and-coming genius setter in Miyagi,
who was apparently quite a sensation.
Personally, I thought he'd make the big jump in his third year of middle school,
but it looks like nothing ever happened.
A genius, huh?
I'm not sure what the actual definition for that is,
but personally, I think a genius is the farthest thing from perfect you can find.
And that is what makes a genius so interesting.
But on the court, well,
you're just a goody two-shoes.
爪痕が残るくらい
拳を固く握り締め
今オレンジの光の中へ
Oh, oh!
Ijiなく汗髪を引き裂く
満ちなるハイステージへ
Jorahway初めはね
抜かしていればいい
傷を恐れ羽ばたかぬ人生なんて
悪性と変わらない
人は一生
夢と感動くらい生きてく
痛いくらい羽根の腎臓
鳥肌が止まらない
命が熱く燃えている
喧嘩着の先
その先で戦う喜びは
勝ち負けすらもどこか遠く
時を止めたこの一瞬が
スローモーションで煌めく
さあ暴れな
勝ち負けすら
敵に対する
その方法で
Finish it!
That was sloppy! And low!
Sorry about that.
Ugh, I hate overhand passes.
Nice to see Tsukishima getting yelled at for once.
When there are only two of you on the court,
there's no one to compensate for your weaknesses.
On the return, they should be aiming for Hyakuzawa, right?
He caves way easier than Kunimi.
But then if Hyakuzawa does manage to get the ball back in the air,
he's going to be the one hitting it over the net.
And if the set is up high, he is definitely going to hit it.
I mean, he is really good at slamming those high sets down.
He doesn't seem all that great at defense, but he's got a lot of stamina.
That, and he's got a really long reach.
So even when you're sure you're going to score, he gets to the ball.
All right, here it goes!
Take it real easy!
Thanks a lot, Hinata.
He really is a lot less stressed now.
Finish it off!
That's definitely not going to be an easy ball to hit.
Should I play back instead of jumping up to block?
No.
If I know Hyakuzawa,
he's going to go for the spike!
One touch!
Really nice job!
Good follow-through!
Crap.
I think it drifted.
Whatever.
It's good enough!
Oh, yeah!
Nice kill, man!
Tsukishima!
That was a nice set!
So what's with the face, then?
I got to see you do some real setting for once,
which got me super excited,
but I hated to see you play better than me!
Well, thank you for the specific and honest opinion.
The pass I made wasn't even that good, though.
Yeah.
I need...
I need to get better at everything, too!
Well, all right, then.
Coach Saito from Shira Torizawa Academy
is, uh...
not feeling well.
So we have a change of plans
and we'll be holding a practice match.
What happened to Coach Saito?
Heard he ate some bad oysters.
Mm-hmm.
So the third years and alumni from Shira Torizawa
will be playing as one team
while the campers form the other team once again.
Today is the last day of your five-day camp,
so do your best to get better results
than you did in the previous scrimmage.
Oh!
The whole Shira Torizawa team!
Man, you don't get a chance like this every day!
Come on, Kunimi, you're just as excited, right?
Be honest!
Secretly, you feel the same way!
You do!
You know you do!
Come to think of it,
that kid from Karasuno,
he was ball boy the last time we did this too.
Why isn't he out there playing?
Uh, it's kind of complicated
and sort of a long story.
But for starters,
he wasn't actually asked to come to the training camp.
What?
How does that make sense?
Got it!
Ushiwaka!
Huh?
Can I ask you a question?
Look, Hinata's actually talking to Ushiwaka.
He sure got some guts.
You go to his school, don't you?
Well, yeah.
But that doesn't make him easy to talk to.
What kind of stuff are you thinking about
when you set up to receive the ball?
Are you sure you don't want to go over there?
Maybe ask Ushiwaka for some tips?
After all, you never know
when we're ever going to see the guy again, right?
Well, I, uh...
Asking a rival for his advice would be...
kinda lame.
Mmm.
No one should be able to say that much
with just their eyes.
Well, when it comes to taking initiative,
there is one thing for certain here.
That number 10 from Karasuno
is definitely one step ahead of you already, at least.
Ushiwaka!
Oh.
What the hell?
I'll be right back.
We'll be right back.
Akiyama's good on the left side, and Hoshiyumi's a great setter.
Yeah, he can play anywhere out there.
You get some interesting results when you shuffle people around.
I'm on a roll.
They're all so good, and they're lifting me up.
Coming at ya!
Man, that was great.
Nice shot!
Hey, you just doubted that my set was good, didn't you?
I was taking a second to be sure.
Can't be too careful.
I'm impressed.
This guy can play any position.
More than anything, this is the time to find hidden talents.
You never know where we might discover some kind of ripe new potential.
And we don't know what the players themselves might learn from this.
Sooner or later, their day will come.
The day when these gifted athletes are going to have to prove their worth, prove their skills.
But I want these boys to always enjoy playing volleyball, no matter what kind of pressure they're under.
It's still a game, after all.
And it might sound incredibly cliche to tell them to take their time.
But, well, it's important advice.
There's no rush.
Mia!
Yeah, yeah, I got it.
Okay.
Here you go.
Yes!
Nice kill, dude.
A really good setter can cast a spell on his Spikers.
He can make his guys believe that they're better and stronger than they really are.
And we've got a really great crop of setters this year.
Hmm.
I only hope the Spikers who have been getting sets from Kageyama Nutsumu don't get too confused when they have to go back to their home teams.
Oh, my God!
Mm-hmm.
Which is kind of cool.
Hmm.
Huh?
Nice serve! Well done!
He says she's gotten really good at jump float serves.
I have to keep up.
It's a bit long, but it's getting better.
Um, thanks!
Noya! Here I come!
Alright, bring it on!
Coach!
Hey, out of go, Specs.
They really like the idea.
Do it again!
Now we just have to find a time that works.
Alright.
Spring Nationals are coming in less than a month.
So I want to play as many matches as we can once our full lineup's back.
Against the strongest opponents we can get.
Agreed.
And as of tomorrow, we'll have them back.
The whole team.
So, how'd you like being a Spiker?
I found it interesting.
And the sets you gave me were really easy to work with as well.
Yeah, I know, right?
Anyone who can't hit one of my sets is a real waste of space.
But anyway, I wanted to ask you.
Are you sure you wouldn't rather be a Spiker?
Uh, why would you ask that?
You've just had this real tense look on your face every time you've made a set.
Yeah, well, that probably has something to do with the fact that you called him a goody two-shoes buddy.
But then, it went away while you were playing on the wing.
You think so?
But I'm not a Spiker.
I'm a setter.
Hmm.
Yeah, I guess you are.
Uh, so, uh, tell me something.
Hmm?
What was it you meant before, calling me goody two-shoes?
Exactly what it sounds like.
You're serious, obedient, and a real good boy.
Hmm.
You've been training with players you don't know in an unfamiliar gym.
And you've all done well.
It's your first step toward the National Youth Team.
You may have felt like you were stumbling in the dark at times.
But I hope you don't think of your practices here as different than the practices you'll be doing back home.
Ideally, you should continue to lift each other up.
Good luck, and keep working hard.
Been a pleasure, guys.
Thank you very much, sir.
Kageyama, see you at Spring Nationals.
Yeah, see ya.
Later, man.
Hmm.
Kageyama, I'll see you around.
And best of luck in the Spring Nationals.
Thanks a lot.
So, which way was the station?
I'll walk you there.
Yes!
I get to play volleyball again tomorrow!
I'm gonna hit so many balls!
Ugh.
The training camp is finally over.
And I still have to play tomorrow?
What is wrong with you?
There's less than a month before Spring Nationals.
Yeah.
Getting the proper amount of rest is part of the training, too.
Hey!
Suki, you gotta give me your phone number.
Come on, man.
I'll give you mine.
Huh?
Yo, Gooshki!
I need your phone number, too, dude!
Dude!
My phone number.
You were the only two I didn't have.
Okay, I'm sending you both a message, so make sure you put my name in!
Hmm.
Hey, um...
Nothing.
I'll see ya.
What the heck?
Uh, how is Kageyama doing?
Uh, he's fine.
Except during test week.
Okay.
How come?
Hmm.
Um, it's just that...
His playing style has...
Changed quite a bit since I knew him.
Hmm?
You need to stop worrying about what happened in middle school.
What you did back then, you thought best.
Uh, whatever.
We're just talking, okay?
It terrifies me, all right?
Is this about the time when no one would hit Kageyama's sets?
It's normal for teammates to fight sometimes, isn't it?
Hmm.
Normal?
When you don't back down, you fight.
That's normal.
He'll be fine.
Don't you worry about him.
Hmm.
Who even cares about Kageyama anyway?
Oh, hey!
We're gonna crush you guys in our next official match.
Hey!
What?
Oh, hell no!
Hinata.
See you around.
Yeah!
Oh, uh, Coach Wachijo, I wanted to thank you for letting us do the camp.
So, what do you think about how we did?
Ah.
Having the two-on-two drills was a good idea.
Oh, good.
I'm glad you think so.
And Karasuno's number ten never even got to practice once?
No, just a ball boy.
Are you serious?
Yep.
But he was more fired up than anyone else there.
And his enthusiasm definitely spread to the other kids.
Hmm.
Huh?
A need.
An overpowering hunger for height.
Whether you're actively aware of it or not.
Whether its presence inside you is something positive or something negative.
Deep down, that hunger is always there.
For both of us.
What we've been given instead of physical stature
is that driving hunger.
I am starving!
Thanks for waiting.
Here are your raw oysters.
Oh?
Oh, man.
This place has got the best oysters around.
Shochew with hot water.
Coming right up!
I am beside you.
Let's go.
What did you do without me for the five days I was gone?
I was a ball boy.
Do you have a key to the club room or the gym?
Mmm, shit.
Let's go.
So, I think the best player there was Goshki.
Oh, but Kunimi and Hyakuzawa, you know, the two meter guy, he's seriously huge.
What about you?
You mean any awesome players?
Yeah.
Of course you did.
Anyone there could probably be in monthly volleyball.
There was a tiny giant.
He was 170 centimeters tall, give or take.
I've never seen him in monthly volleyball.
But I guarantee, of all the guys they invited to that intensive, he was one of the best.
God.
He was a hundred times better than you.
You could have left that part out.
So he was one of the best.
Do I really need to know more than that?
Did you really need to add that last part?
Did you really?
Hey, I knew you'd be here.
And what?
You can't wait two seconds before you're at each other's throats?
Tanaka!
How do you two ding-dongs keep finding new things to fight about?
It's a real talent.
Telling you what.
So.
If you want to, you can fly even higher.
Kenji!
Yes, sir!
We just agreed to a last-minute practice for next week, so be ready.
Who are we playing?
Karasuno.
Ah!
We'll be playingazio.
We'll be playing.
Mm hmm.
Thank you.
Next time, Going Higher.